Guide to the David Barsamian Collection of Alternative Radio Audio Recordings OH.088
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
David Barsamian Collection of Alternative Radio Audio Recordings
1990-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Barsamian, David
OH.088
2.5 Linear Feet in 7 cassette boxes and 1 CD box.
292 audiocassettes
12 CD-ROM
The David Barsamian Collection of Alternative Radio Audio Recordings contains audio recordings of Alternative Radio, the independent radio show established by David Barsamian in 1986. Episodes in this collection range from 1990-2002, and cover sociopolitical topics such as media censorship and corporatization, anti-war movements, global conflicts, and racism and classism in the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession number related to this collectoin is 2014.128.
Arrangement
The episodes are arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
David Barsamian is an Armenian American investigative journalist, radio broadcaster, and author based in Boulder, Colorado. In 1986 he founded Alternative Radio, a public access program that covers international and domestic politics and social movements. In addition to hosting the weekly radio show, Barsamian has published many of his extensive interviews with figures such as Noam Chomsky, Edward Said, Howard Zinn, Eqbal Ahmad, Arundhati Roy, and Richard Wolff.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596, with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The David Barsamian Collection of Alternative Radio Audio Recordings contains audio recordings of Alternative Radio. The episodes range from 1990-2002, and cover sociopolitical topics such as media censorship and corporatization, anti-war movements, global imperialism and colonialism, environmentalism, the Israeli-Palestinian Conflict, the Iraq War, the Gulf War, racism and Civil Rights history, economic inqueality, U.S. domestic policy, and the U.S. prison industrial complex. Episode guests featured in this collection include Angela Davis, Noam Chomsky, Edward Said, Eqbal Ahmad, Ralph Nader, Arundhati Roy, and Howard Zinn, among others.
Alternative radio broadcasting.; Alternative mass media -- United States; Mass media criticism -- United States; Audiocassettes.; Environmentalism; Peace movements -- United States.; Racism -- United States.; Prison-industrial complex; Chomsky, Noam; Zinn, Howard, 1922-2010; Nader, Ralph; Said, Edward W.; Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944-; Ahmad, Eqbal
- Eqbal Ahmad: "Roots of the Gulf Crisis," Boston, Massachusetts, November 17, 1990 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0216)
- Manning Marable: "The Life and Legacy of Malcolm X," Denver, Colorado, February 21, 1992
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0001)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0294)
- Kwame Ture: "Black History," Denver, Colorado, March 2, 1992 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0002)
- Andre Zimbalist: "The Economics of Baseball," Conway, New Hampshire, August 19, 1992 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0003)
- Michael Parenti: "The Struggle for Democracy," Berkeley, California, October 23, 1992 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0004)
- Helena Norberg-Hodge: "Rethinking Development," Boulder, Colorado, November 30, 1992 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0005)
- Helen Caldicott: "If You Love This Planet," Boulder, Colorado, April 6, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0006)
- Cornel West: "Race Matters," Brunswick, Maine, April 15, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0007)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0295)
- June Jordan: "Freedom in the U.S.A.," Boulder, Colorado, September 23, 1993; cuid43299 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0008)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Duration: 61 minutes
- Edward Said: "The Israel / PLO Accord: A Critical Assessment," New York, New York, September 27, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0009)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0296)
- Winona La Duke: "Social Justice, Racism and the Environmental Model," Boulder, Colorado, September 28, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0010)
- Haunani-Kay Trask: "Environmental Racism in Hawaii and the Pacific Basin," Boulder, Colorado, September 29, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0011)
- Kristin Dawkins and Keith Maskus: "NAFTA Debate," Boulder, Colorado, October 1, 1993
  - Part one (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0012)
  - Part two (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0013)
- Russell Means: "Knowing Who You Are: Lessons from Native America," Boulder, Colorado, October 11, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0014)
- Manning Marable: "Race, Education and Multiculturalism," Denver, Colorado, October 22, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0015)
- Branka Magas and Christopher Hitchens: "The Destruction of Yugoslavia," Chicago, Illinois and Washington, D.C., October 30, 1993 - December 9, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0024)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0297)
- Herbert Schiller: "Corporate Control of Information," New Brunswick, New Jersey, November 12, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0016)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0298)
- Naseer Aruri: "Prospects for Peace and Palestine," Wichita, Kansas, November 13, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0017)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0293)
- Howard Zinn: "The Use and Abuse of History," Denver, Colorado, November 13, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0018)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0299)
- Dennis Brutus: "South Africa: Transition to Freedom?" Denver, Colorado, November 19, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0019)
- Elaine Bernard: "Solidarity: An Injury to One is an Injury to All," Denver, Colorado, December 3, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0020)
- Larry Birns: "U. S. Policy in Latin America," Washington, D.C., December 9, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0021)
- Robin Broad: "Plundering Paradise: The Philippines," Washington, D.C., December 9, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0022)
- Ken Silverstein: "Media Reporting on the Third World," Washington, D.C., December 10, 1993
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0023)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0300)
- Noam Chomsky: "The Clinton Vision," Washington, D.C., December 10, 1993 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0025)
- Julianne Malveaux: "Economic Justice: The Legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.," Denver, Colorado, January 18, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0026)
- Jennifer Harbury: "Guatemala: Bridge of Courage," Columbia, Maryland, January 29, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0027)
- Jonathan Fox: "Mexico: The Chiapas Uprising," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 1, 1994
  - Original recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0028)
  - Access CD (Box 1, Cd 088_0301)
- Norman Solomon: "False Hope: The Politics of Bill Clinton," Santa Cruz, California, February 7, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0029)
- Ralph Nader: "GATT: Global Corporatism," Washington, D.C., February 28, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0030)
- Philip Agee: "The CIA and Cuba," Santa Cruz, California, March 9, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0031)
- Philip Agee: "The Re-emergence of Fascism in Europe," Portland, Oregon, March 10, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0032)
- Adolfo Aguilar: "Mexico After NAFTA and Chiapas," Boulder, Colorado, March 11, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0033)
- Ali Mazrui: "Africa: Myths and Realities," Boulder, Colorado, March 11, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0034)
- Allan Nairn: "East Timor: A Case of Genocide," Portland, Oregon, April 1, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0035)
- Erwin Knoll: "The 1st Amendment Under Attack," Gainesville, Florida, April 2, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0036)
- Barbara Trent: "The Making of the Panama Deception," Gainesville, Florida, April 2, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0037)
- Molly Ivins: "American Political Culture and Other Jokes," Boulder, Colorado, April 5, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0038)
- Robert McChesney: "The Corporate Takeover of Broadcasting," Iowa City, Iowa, April 7, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0039)
- John Cavanagh: "Global Dreams: Imperial Corporations," Washington, D.C., April 13, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0040)
- Christopher Simpson: "Science of Coercion: Psychological Warfare," Washington, D.C., April 14, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0041)
- Bernie Sanders: "Single Payer Health Care," Boulder, Colorado, April 23, 1994 (Box 2, Audiocassette 088_0042)
- Robert Williams: "Sovereignty, Racism and Human Rights," Missoula, Montana, April 28, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0043)
- Michael Parenti: "The Control of History," Los Angeles, California, May 11, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0044)
- Barbara Ehrenreich: "Trash Media," Woods Hole, Massachusetts, June 7, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0045)
- Ron Daniels: "Media and Organizing," Woods Hole, Massachusetts, June 17, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0046)
- Ralph Nader: "Corporate Power: Profits Before People," Denver, Colorado, September 1, 1994
  - Part one (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0047)
  - Part two (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0048)
- Angela Davis: "Report from Harlem," New York, New York, September 9, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0049)
- Winston Nagan: "Bosnia: A Question of Genocide," Gainesville, Florida, September 12, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0050)
- Danny Kennedy: "The World Bank / IMF: 50 Years is Enough," Boulder, Colorado, September 20, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0051)
- Mab Segrest: "Backlash: Community or Chaos in the 21st Century," Gainesville, Florida, September 21, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0052)
- Vandana Shiva: "The Recovery of the Commons," Colorado Springs, Colorado, September 25, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0053)
- Chip Berlet: "The Rise of the Religious Right," New York, New York, September 28, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0054)
- Amiri Baraka: "Jazz and African American Culture," New York, New York, October 13, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0055)
- Noam Chomsky: "Containing the Crisis at Home and Abroad," Chicago, Illinois, October 18, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0056)
- Holly Sklar: "Scapegoating the Poor," Raleigh, North Carolina, October 29, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0057)
- Paul Farmer: "Haiti: U.S. Intervention and the Struggle for Democracy," Washington, D.C., November 2, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0058)
- Gar Alperovitz: "Hiroshima: New Facts and Old Myths," Ames, Iowa, November 7, 1994 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0059)
- Noam Chomsky: "The 'Peace Process' in the Mideast," Raleigh, North Carolina, November 12, 1994
  - Part one (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0060)
  - Part two (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0061)
- Michael Albert: "Toward a New Economic Model," Portland, Oregon, January 21, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0062)
- Doug Henwood: "Economy Up, People Down," New York, New York, February 1, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0063)
- Bobby Seale: "The Black Panther Party," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 2, 1995 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0282)
- Michael Eric Dyson: "Malcolm X and the Politics of Race," Boulder, Colorado, February 2, 1995
  - Audio recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0064)
  - Audio recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0223)
- Bobby Seale: "The Black Panther Party," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 2, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0065)
- Saul Landau: "The Newt World Order," Santa Cruz, California, February 17, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0066)
- Laura Flanders: "Media and the Contract with America," Boulder, Colorado, March 1, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0067)
- Kwame Ture: "Black History," Denver, Colorado, March 2, 1992 (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0283)
- Lani Guinier: "Race: Creating a National Conversation," Boulder, Colorado, March 7, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0068)
- Helen Caldicott: "Technology, Spirituality and The Future of The Planet," Portland, Oregon, March 28, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0069)
- Michio Kaku: "The Legacy of Nuclear Weapons," Boulder, Colorado, April 4, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0070)
- Peter Dale Scott: "The Politics of Global Drug Trafficking," Durango, Colorado, April 4, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0071)
- Jeff Cohen: "Rush Limbaugh's Reign of Error," Kalamazoo, Michigan, April 5, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0072)
- Frances Fox Piven: "Welfare: Myths and Facts," Brooklyn, New York, April 6, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0073)
- Elaine Bernard: "NAFTA: A Critical Reassessment," Boulder, Colorado, April 8, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0074)
- Jeremy Brecher: "Globalization: The Race to the Bottom," Boston, Massachusetts, April 9, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0075)
- Larry Bensky: "The Right-Wing Agenda in Congress," Tampa, Florida, April 14, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0076)
- Edward Said: "Shrinking Horizon of Hope: Mideast Peace Process," Medford, Massachusetts, April 20-25, 1995
  - Part one, April 20, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0077)
  - Part two, April 25, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0078)
- Noam Chomsky: "Class War: The Attack on Working People," Cambridge, Massachusetts, May 9, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0079)
- Chip Berlet and Holly Sklar: "Oklahoma, Militias and Conspiracy Theories," Cambridge, Massachusetts, May 10, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0080)
- Ward Churchill: "Fascism, the FBI and Native Americans," Boulder, Colorado, September 6, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0081)
- Jeff Cohen: "Media Monopolies: Corporate Merger Mania," Boulder, Colorado, September 8, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0082)
- Barbara Ehrenreich: "A Progressive Vision for Social Change," Tampa, Florida, September 22, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0083)
- Michael Parenti: "Fascism: The False Revolution," Berkeley, California, September 23, 1995 (Box 3, Audiocassette 088_0084)
- Ruben Blades: "A Latino Response to Cultural Cleansing," San Antonio, Texas, September 28, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0085)
- Michael Parenti: "Costs of Empire," Madison, Wisconsin, September 28, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0086)
- Noam Chomsky: "Robbing People Blind: The U.S. Economic System," Cambridge, Massachusetts, October 31, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0087)
- William Sales: "Malcolm X and the Struggle for Black Liberation," New York, New York, October 17, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0088)
- Manning Marable: "Beyond Black and White: Rethinking Race," New York, New York, October 26, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0089)
- Cornel West: "The Radical Democratice Tradition," Portland, Oregon, October 27, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0090)
- Noam Chomsky: "Robbing People Blind: The U.S. Economic System," Cambridge, Massachusetts, November 3, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0091)
- Winona La Duke: "An Indigenous View of North America," Raleigh, North Carolina, November 13, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0092)
- Howard Zinn: "A People's History of the United States," Portland, Oregon, November 20, 1995
  - Part one (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0093)
  - Part two (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0094)
- Ralph Nader: "Washington Rules," Washington, D.C., December 8-9, 1995
  - Part one, December 8, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0095)
  - Part two, December 9, 1995 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0096)
- Frances Fox Piven and Richard Cloward: "The Politics of Family Values," St. Petersburg, Florida, January 22, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0097)
- Lifton, Smith and Balakian: "Turkish Denial of the Armenian Genocide," New York, New York, January 29, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0098)
- Chuck Collins and Felice Yeskel: "Ending Corporate Welfare," Boston, Massachusetts, February 7, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0099)
- Mumia Abu-Jamal: "From Death Row," Waynesburg, Pennsylvania, February 8, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0100)
- Tony Mazzocchi: "Labor Party Advocates - A New Party," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 8, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0101)
- Ben Bagdikian: "Journalism and the Media Monopoly," Berkeley, California, February 28, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0102)
- Sara Diamond: "The Politics of the Christian Right," Berkeley, California, February 28, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0103)
- Robert Parry: "The Art of Investigative Journalism," San Francisco, California, March 2, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0104)
- Urvashi Vaid: "Virtual Equality: Gay and Lesbian Liberation," San Francisco, California, March 2, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0105)
- David Montgomery: "The Labor Union Movement: History and Prospects," Cambridge, Massachusetts, March 7, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0106)
- Howard Zinn et al: "Stop the Death Penalty!" Cambridge, Massachusetts, March 11, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0107)
- Tania Rosario and Mateo Roose: "Organize! Union Summer," Boulder, Colorado, March 12, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0108)
- Molly Ivins: "The State of U.S. Politics," Boulder, Colorado, April 8, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0109)
- Noam Chomsky: "The Myth of the Free Market," Cambridge, Massachusetts, April 13, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0110)
- Herbert Schiller: "The Corporate Packaging of the Public Mind," Portland, Oregon, April 18, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0111)
- Jim Hightower: "Money and Politics," Albuquerque, New Mexico, May 18, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0112)
- Ron Daniels: "Racism: Past and Present," Woods Hole, Massachusetts, June 12, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0113)
- Holly Sklar: "The Economics of Greed," Denver, Colorado, June 13, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0114)
- Nader, Shiva, Bhagwati, et al.: "Debate on the WTO and Globalization," Los Angeles, California, August 19, 1996
  - Part one (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0263)
  - Part two (Box 8, Audiocassette 088_0264)
- Ralph Nader: "Beyond Politics As Usual: Nader for President," Los Angeles, California, August 19, 1996
  - Part one (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0115)
  - Part two (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0116)
- Ralph Nader: "Citizen Nader," Los Angeles, California, August 20, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0117)
- Ralph Nader: "The Future of Public Interest Law," Los Angeles, California, August 20, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0118)
- John Cavanagh: "Global Economic Apartheid," Takoma Park, Maryland, September 19, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0119)
- Michael Moore: "Downsize This!" Denver, Colorado, September 29, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0120)
- Winona La Duke: "Recovering the Land: Native Americans and the Law," Boulder, Colorado, October 11, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0121)
- David Korten: "When Corporations Rule the World," Madison, Wisconsin, October 12, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0122)
- Mimi Abramovitz: "The Attack on Women and Welfare," New York, New York, October 31, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0123)
- Medea Benjamin: "Nike, Reebok and the Global Sweatshop," Madison, Wisconsin, November 20, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0124)
- Robert McChesney: "The Global Media System," Madison, Wisconsin, December 2, 1996 (Box 4, Audiocassette 088_0125)
- Randy Albelda: "The War on the Poor," Cambridge, Massachusetts, December 17, 1996 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0126)
- Howard Lyman: "The Case for Vegetarianism," Boulder, Colorado, January 22, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0127)
- Charlie Kernaghan: "Reports from the Global Factory: Kathie Lee, The Gap and Disney," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 6, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0128)
- Noam Chomsky: "Propaganda and Control of the Public Mind," Cambridge, Massachusetts, February 7, 1997
  - Part one (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0129)
  - Part two (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0130)
- John Stauber: "Lies, Damn Lies and Public Relations," Madison, Wisconsin, February 8, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0131)
- "CIA Covert Actions and Drug Trafficking," Washington, D.C., February 13, 1997
  - Part one (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0132)
  - Part two (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0133)
- Richard Grossman: "Revoking Corporate Charters," Boulder, Colorado, February 13, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0134)
- Jose Ramos-Horta: "East Timor, Indonesia and the U.S.," New York, New York, February 20, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0135)
- Loretta Ross: "Welfare, Scapegoating and Human Rights," New York, New York, February 26, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0136)
- Urvashi Vaid: "Building Coalitions: Bridging Difference," Boulder, Colorado, March 2, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0137)
- Todd Gitlin: "The Future of Progressive Politics," New York, New York, March 6, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0138)
- Linda Gordon: "How Welfare Became a Dirty Word," Portland, Oregon, March 7, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0139)
- Eric Foner: "Who is an American?" Boulder, Colorado, March 11, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0140)
- Michael Parenti: "The Hidden Ideology of the Mass Media," Burlington, Vermont, April 9, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0141)
- William Greider: "The Manic Logic of Global Capitalism," Madison, Wisconsin, April 12, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0142)
- Barbara Ehrenreich: "The End of Caring," Portland, Oregon, April 14, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0143)
- Nadine Strossen: "The Case for Affirmative Action," Boulder, Colorado, April 22, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0144)
- Vandana Shiva: "Biopiracy: The Plunder of Nature and Knowledge," Boulder, Colorado, April 29, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0145)
- Angela Davis: "The Prison Industrial Complex," Colorado Springs, Colorado, May 5, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0146)
- Doug Henwood: "Wall Street," New York, New York, June 25, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0147)
- Norman Solomon: "The Orchestration of News," Berkeley, California, August 11, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0148)
- Martin Lee: "The CIA and LSD: Acid Dreams," Menlo Park, California, September 13, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0149)
- Chuck Collins: "Economic Inequality: The Growing Divide," Madison, Wisconsin, September 27, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0150)
- Elaine Bernard: "Worker Solidarity and Human Rights," Denver, Colorado, October 4, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0151)
- Noam Chomsky: "An Inquiry into Global Capitalism," Amherst, Massachusetts, October 3, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0152)
- Helen Caldicott: "Ecology and the Human Spirit," Eugene, Oregon, October 2, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0153)
- John Robbins: "Diet for a New America," Boulder, Colorado, October 6, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0154)
- Howard Zinn: "The Case of Sacco and Vanzetti," Boston, Massachusetts, October 9, 1997 (Box 7, Audiocassette 088_0243)
- Jonathan Kozol: "Race and Class in Public Education," Albany, New York, October 17, 1997
  - Audio recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0155)
  - Audio recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 088_0199)
- Edward Said: "Israel and Palestine: The Challenge Ahead," Washington, D.C., November 2, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0156)
- Dave Foreman: "In Defense of the Wild," Boulder, Colorado, November 5, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0157)
- Martin Lee: "Resurgent Fascism: The Beast Awakens," Boulder, Colorado, November 5, 1997 (Box 5, Audiocassette 088_0158)